A Guide to the 8th Evacuation Hospital 1941-2011
Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
- Correspondence from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser April 1945, 5 V-mail letters (Box-folder 35-049)
- Correspondence from T.M. Whitten to Gladys Kinser April 1945, 1 ALS, 1 envelope (Box-folder 35-050)
- V-mail from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser May 1945, 4 V-mail letters, 1 V-mail anniversary card (Box-folder 35-051)
- Correspondence from Prentice Kinser and T.M. Whitten to Gladys Kinser May 1945, 2 ALS, 2 envelopes (Box-folder 35-052)
- V-mail from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser June 1945, 2 V-mail letters (Box-folder 35-053)
- Correspondence from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser June 1945, 2 ALS, 2 envelopes (Box-folder 35-054)
- Correspondence from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser July 1945, 4 V-mail (original) letters, 1 ALS, 1 envelope, 1 photo, Italian lire, restaurant bill (Box-folder 35-055)
- Correspondence from Prentice Kinser and R.W. Whitten to Gladys Kinser and from T.M. Whitten to Mrs. L.R. Whitten August 1945, 7 V-mail (original) letters, 2 ALS, 2 envelopes (Box-folder 35-056)
- Correspondence from Prentice Kinser to Gladys Kinser and from Gladys Kinser to Prentice Kinser September 1945, 5 V-mail (original) letters, 1 ALS, 1 envelope (Box-folder 35-057)
- Correspondence from Prentice Kinser and T.M. Whitten to Gladys Kinser October 1945, 7 V-mail (original) letters, 1 ALS, 1 envelope (Box-folder 35-058)
- Correspondence from R.W. Whitten to Mrs. L.R. Whitten November 1945, 1 ALS, 1 envelope (Box-folder 35-059)
- Correspondence from R.W. Whitten to Prentice and Gladys Kinser May 1947, 1 ALS, 1 envelope (Box-folder 35-060)
- Life "Halloran Hospital: Army brings North Africa wounded home to the U.S. for treatment" 1943 May 3, 1 magazine (Box-folder 36-001)
  Some of the 8th Evac patients were returned to receive treatment at Halloran Hospital.
- The Shelby News Senior Gazette Class '24 Shelbyville High School 1924 June 5, newspaper (Box-folder 36-002)
  The photo of the graduating class includes Prentice Kinser.
- Richmond Times-Dispatch "War Is Declared by Great Britain" 1939 September 4, newspaper (Box-folder 36-003)
- Richmond Times-Dispatch, sunday Magazine and Book Review "The First Six Month of War" 1940 March 17, newspaper (Box-folder 36-004)
- The Daily Progress "Italy Enters War against British and French; Roosevelt May Refer to Mussolini in Speech" 1940 June 10, newspaper (Box-folder 36-005)
- The Daily Progress French sue Germans for Armistice; Hitler to See Il Duce on Terms; London vows to Continue War" 1940 June 17, newspaper (Box-folder 36-006)
- Richmond Times-Dispatch U.S. Joins Britain in Alliance to Crush 'Nazi Tyranny' and Reconstruct World" 1941 August 15, newspaper (Box-folder 36-007)
- Danville Commercial Appeal "Japs Start War" 1941 December 8, newspaper (Box-folder 36-008)
- The Bee U.S. Declares War; Fleet Is Hit Hard 1941 December 8, newspaper (Box-folder 36-009)
- Army Times Carolina Air-Ground War Starts 1942 July 25, newspaper (Box-folder 36-010)
- Army Times "Air-Ground Maneuvers Speed Up" 1942 August 1, newspaper (Box-folder 36-011)
- The Daily Progress "Nazi Forces Leaving Stalingrad" 1942 December 2, newspaper (Box-folder 36-012)
- The Stars and Stripes "Sweatin' It Out..." 1944 July 1, newspaper clipping (Box-folder 36-013)
- The Stars and Stripes Mediterranean "German Drive Slowing Down 1944 December 24, newspaper (Box-folder 36-014)
- The Daily Progress "Winners in Bond Contest Named" 1945 February 10, newspaper clipping (Box-folder 36-015)
- Richmond Times-Dispatch "President Roosevelt Dies" 1945 April 13, newspaper (Box-folder 36-016)
- The Stars and Stripes Mediterranean Germans in Central Europe, Norway Close to Surrender 1945 May 6, newspaper (Box-folder 36-017)
- The Daily Progress Victory Day Edition, "Nazis Surrender!" 1945 May 7, newspaper (Box-folder 36-018)
- The Stars and Stripes Mediterranean "It's All Over Over Here 1945 May 8, newspaper (Box-folder 36-019)
- Richmond Times-Dispatch Nazi Surrender Is Official; Prague Fight Is Still Raging" 1945 May 8, newspaper (Box-folder 36-020)
- Richmond Times-Dispatch "How Allied Victory Was Won" 1945 May 8, newspaper (Box-folder 36-021)
- The Daily Progress "They Piloted the Atomic Bomber" 1945 August 9, newspaper (Box-folder 36-022)
- Richmond Times-Dispatch "Russia Enters War" 1945 August 9, newspaper (Box-folder 36-023)
- The Stars and Stripes Mediterranean "Russians Storm Manchuria; 2nd Atom Bomb Hits Japs 1945 August 10, newspaper (Box-folder 36-024)
- The Stars and Stripes Mediterranean "Japs Offer Surrender" 1945 August 11, newspaper (Box-folder 36-025)
- The Stars and Stripes Mediterranean "Japs Say They Accept" 1945 August 14, newspaper (Box-folder 36-026)
- The Stars and Stripes Mediterranean "Peace at Last" 1945 August 15, newspaper (Box-folder 36-027)
- Richmond Times-Dispatch "Japs Quit" 1945 August 15, newspaper (Box-folder 36-028)
- The Stars and Stripes Mediterranean "Laval Shot by Firing Squad" 1945 October 16, newspaper (Box-folder 36-029)
- photos of Cannes, Milan, Venice, Rome and unknown locations most n.d., others 1945, 21 photographs (Box-folder 37-001)
  Monument inscription IOANNES BAPTISTA REZZONICO ...; ISTITUTO NAZIONALE PER LE RELAZIONI CULTURALI CON L'ESTERO ROMA Via Quattro Fontane 20, SERVIZIO FOTOGRAFICO 12150 Reparti italinai di guastatori attaccano un capo saldo nemico sul fronte egiziano; Venice, May 8, 1945; Panorama of Venice from Campanile, May 8, 1945; Prentice Kinser, Venice, May 8, 1945; King Victor Emmanuel Memorial; Easter Sunday, Pietramala, Ruth Buffington and Prentice Kinser; Palazzo delle Assicurazioni Generali di Venezia; building with quote from Mussolini: ... vostra madre, dovete, con la stessa purezza di sentimento, amare la madre comune: la Patria nostra; Levin Islands from Super Cannes; funiculare going to Super Cannes, June 1945; beach at Cannes; Walk along waterfront in Cannes; Hotel Carlton and waterfront at Cannes; Monaco France where Monte Carlo is located; Filling station in Milan, Italy where Mussolini and henchman were hung
- photos of Portici, Italy, Rome, unknown locations most n.d., others 1945, 16 photographs (Box-folder 37-002)
  6 photos from Portici, Italy, some dated March 1945, 2 of Prentice Kinser; waterfall and statuary in gardens; Prentice Kinser amongst the Cupids, February 1945; the 1st Christian church in Italy (Rome); Mussolini's balcony, Piazza Venezia, Rome; the Roman Forum; map in stone on old Roman wall of Holy Roman empire at its height; a pagan temple?; Roman amphitheater or Colosseum; photo of woman and 2 little girls with notation on back: You can't tell who I am but notice the high sign given by Carolyn.
- Prentice Kinser n.d., 1942, 7 photographs (Box-folder 37-003)
  Photos all include Prentice Kinser, one shows him having an award pinned on, another is the officers of the 8th Evac at the Italian consulate in Casablance in December 1942
- Prentice Kinser and unidentified men n.d., 9 photo strips (Box-folder 37-004)
  Some photos taken in Pompeii.
- unidentified photos n.d., 32 photographs (Box-folder 37-005)
- unidentified photos n.d., 37 photographs (Box-folder 37-006)
- picture postcards n.d., 16 postcards (Box-folder 36-007)
  3 photos of Jungfraujoch inside the Gletscherpalast or ice palace, one outside, A. G. Wehrli; Signpost to Rothorn, Kunstverlag H.C. Maeder; Wagenbachbrunne, Luzern, Wehrli & Vouga & Co.; Brienz, Dorfpartie, Kunstverlag H.C. Maeder; Thun und die Alpen, Wehrli & Vouga & Co.; Polarhunde auf dem Jungfraujoch, Wehrli & Vouga & Co.; Oberried a. Brienzersee, Verlag Schild-Bichsel; Thun, Schloss, Wehrli & Vouga & Co.; Thun, Hauptgasse, Wehrli & Vouga & Co.; Roma - Piazza di Spagna; Roma - Piazza Venezia; Luzern. Museggtrume, Wehrli & Vouga & Co.; L. Thomann Brienz
- professional photos of Pisa and Luzern n.d., 12 photographs, 1 photo strip booklet (Box-folder 37-008)
- unidentified photo negatives n.d., photo negatives (Box-folder 37-009)
- unidentified photo negatives n.d., photo negatives (Box-folder 37-010)
- Prentice Kinser diary n.d., 1942-1943, 3 strips of film negatives, diary (Box-folder 37-011)
  Diary was given to Prentice Kinser by his wife just before leaving Fort Benning on Sept. 15, 1942. First entry is September 15, 1942 and continues into 1943. Inside the front cover is written: "Note Made Oct. 11, 1943 Bet made with Maury Lebauer in presence of J.O. McNeil, John Guerrant, Calvin Drayer in front of J.O's tent night of Oct. 10, 1943 ... in Paestum in Italy. If war is over Jan 1st 1944 I owe him 10.00. If war is not over by June 30, 1944 he owes me $15.00. On continent of Europe 5.00 even on War is over Jan 1st 1944, 5.00. 2 to one its over by June 30 1944."
- "Diplomates of the American Board of Orthopaedic Sugery 1942-1943" 1942 August 1, 1 pamphlet (Box-folder 37-012)
- "Drill Gun Manual of Arms" n.d., 1 pamphlet (Box-folder 37-013)
- 8th Evac hospital layout n.d., 1 Doc (Box-folder 36-014)
- European guides: Italy n.d., 4 pamphlets (Box-folder 37-015)
  Napoli map and excursions, Church of Santa Croce, Florence, A Soldier's Guide to Florence, Soldier's Guide to Italy
- European guides: Switzerland n.d., 13 pamphlets (Box-folder 37-016)
  Maps and guidebooks to Switzerland in general and Berne, Lucerne, and Jungfrau
- "Mission Accomplished: Africa, Sicily, Italy" 1945, 1 pamphlet (Box-folder 37-017)
- Money from Africa 1941, n.d., 5 bills (Box-folder 37-018)
  The bills are marked Casablanca, Nov. 18, 1942; Marrakeich, Jan. 15, 1943; Rabat, Feb. 15, 1943; Port Lyautey, Feb. 1943; Algiers, Maison Blanche, Cap Matifou, Oran, Aug. 1943
- "Mud, Mules, and Mountains" by Bill Mauldin and cartoons by Mauldin 1944, 1 pamphlet, 3 newspaper clippings (Box-folder 37-019)
- Orders, Pay and Allowance Account, and Statement of Commisioned Service from the War Department For Prentice Kinser 1942, 2 telegrams, 3 TD, 1 pamphlet, 1 AD (Box-folder 37-020)
  Page 6 (top) of the pamphlet has instructions for Maj. Prentice Kinser to be moved from the 3d Evac Hosp., Wadesboro, NC, effective about Aug. 24, 1942 to the 8th Evac Hosp. at Ft. Benning, Ga.
- Report of investigation 1942 August 1, 1 TD (Box-folder 37-021)
  Kinser was the investigating officer for a case which resulted in a Summary Court Martial.
- Saint Domenico and Saint Matteo cards n.d., 2 cards (Box-folder 37-022)
- "'We were all in it together': Medicine and Nursing in the 8th Evacuation Hospital, 1942-1945" by Patricia Anne Kinser; invitation 2011, 1 TD, 1 invitation (Box-folder 37-023)
  Patricia Kinser's paper "explore[s] the history of the 8th Evacuation Hospital in World War II within a narrative describing the experiences of Dr. Prentice Kinser Jr., an orthopedic surgeon, and Dorothy Sandridge Gloor, a surgical nurse in the unit." The paper is in partial fulfillment of requirements for GNUR 8230: Historical Inquiry in Nursing. The invitation is to an open house in Historical Collections on November 15, 2011 where Patricia Kinser presented her paper, and the donation of her grandfather's papers was celebrated.
- "We Were There: From Gruber to the Brenner Pass" With the 88th Division, Italy, Compiled by Headquarters, 88th Infantry Division. n.d., 1 pamphlet (Box-folder 37-024)
- ""'We were all in it together': Medicine and Nursing in the 8th Evacuation Hospital, 1942-1945" by Patricia Anne Kinser in "Windows in Time" 2011 November, 1 journal (Box-folder 37-025)
  This article is a shorter version of Kinser's paper for the GNUR 8230 class.
- Group photos including Shock Team, Receiving n.d., 3 photos (Box-folder 38-001)
  The Shock Team is shown sitting on stairs. top row: Mallow, Holsinger, Morris; bottom row: Ward, Kidd. The receiving team is from left to right: Didier, Buonovicino, Wanderer, Horwath, De Ross, Salmon. The third group shot shows top row: Bara, Erk, Johnsmeyer, Padula; bottom row: Johnson, Meckle, Pratt, Glaser.
- Winter in Pietramala Winter 1944-1945, 17 photos (Box-folder 38-002)
  The photos all show Pietramala in the winter snow. Also included is the crest of Radicosa Pass, tents, Mt Beni, Chapel tent, Christmas wine barrel, town of Pietramala, winterized ward tents
- Christmas and storm December 1944, 5 photos (Box-folder 38-003)
  The storm pictures include the wreck of the mess hall. One Christmas picture shows three women; the other shows a man in front of an evergreen tree.
- Frederick Broadfoot and Frances Wells wedding February 23, 1945, 8 photos (Box-folder 38-004)
  The wedding took place in the American Episcopal Church in FLorence. Chaplain Laird performed the ceremony.
- Spring and Mt. Beni Spring 1945, 2 photos (Box-folder 38-005)
- Easter service April 1, 1945, 3 photos (Box-folder 38-006)
  Shows altar, congregants and clergy.
- Hilda Franklin and Richard P. Bell wedding May 26, 1945, 1 photo (Box-folder 38-007)
- "Back to the Beginning for the 8th Evac Hospital in Morocco in World War Two 70 Years Ago" by Herbert Y. Reynolds November 12, 2013, 1 TD (Box-folder 38-008)
  Text of a presentation given in Historical Collections for the Sloane Society by Dr. Reynolds.
- "Back to the Beginning for the Eighth Evacuation Hospital in Morocco in World War II 70 Years Ago" by Herbert Y. Reynolds and (by invitation) Anne Leavell Reynolds and Lucie Leavell Vogel 2014, reprint, 4 copies (Box-folder 38-009)
  Reprint of the article in the Transactions of the American Clinical and Climatological Association, Vol. 125.
- Letter from Jessie Broadfoot Boyer to Joan Echtenkamkp Klein with photocopy of an album made by Boyer of her parents', Frances E. Wells and Frederick M. Broadfoot, time serving in WWII. 2014, TLs, photocopy of album (Box-folder 38-010)
  The album contains photographs, list of rations for their wedding reception, and some of her parent's memories of serving overseas. Wells served with the 8th Evac as a nurse. Broadfoot was a captain with the Cryptography Unit of the Signal Corps.
- 8TH EVACUATION HOSPITAL, PIETRAMALA, ITALY, 1944 N.D., 1 DRAWING (Box-folder HOUSED IN MISC. OVERSIZE COLLECTION, MS-43, BOX 2)